A Guide to the Papers of the League of Women Voters 1949-1985
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the League of Women Voters 1949-1985
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8974-c
This collection consists of 1,500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library on November 6, 1985.
Scope and Content Information
League papers contain local, state and national materials. The national papers include national convention workbooks, 1964-1982; national publications including issues of "The National Voter," 1970-1984; and national Board and Council reports, 1970-1981. Virginia papers include convention workbooks, 1967-1985; state council reports, 1970-1980; and issues of "The Virginia Voter," 1971-1985.
Local papers include the "action" file, 1970-1980, of correspondence and statements on local issues; minutes of the annual and Board of Directors meetings, 1970-1979; by-laws, 1949-1981; the bulletin of the League, 1969-1985; agendas and membership lists; and voter service files re: registration drives and questions asked of candidates, 1964-1979; committee studies; and miscellaneous league publications.
Topics of interest to the local league include annexation, day care, education, housing, juvenile offenders, land use, library services, local government, recreational facilities, transportation, water quality, women's rights, and zoning.
Contents List
- League of Women Voters of the U.S.
  - Convention Workbooks 1964-1982, 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Impact on Issues 1978-1984 (Box 1)
  - In League 1980 (Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Catalog 1981-1985 (Box 1)
  - National Board Reports 1970-1979, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - National Council Reports 1971-1981 (Box 2)
  - The National Voter 1970-1984, 7 folders (Box 2)
- League of Women Voters of Virginia
  - Convention Workbooks 1967-1985, 9 notebooks (Box 3)
  - State Council Reports 1970-1980, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - The Virginia Voter League of Women Voters of Charlottesville and Albemarle County 1971-1985 (Box 3)
  - Action Notebooks 1971-1976, 4 notebooks (Box 4)
  - Action Notebooks 1977-1980, 4 notebooks (Box 5)
  - Annual Meeting Minutes 1970-1979, 10 notebooks (Box 6)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes 1970-1979, 9 notebooks (Box 6)
  - By Laws 1949-1981 (Box 7)
  - Guide to Government 1958-1980 (Box 7)
  - League of Women Voters Bulletin 1969-1978 (Box 7)
  - League of Women Voters Bulletin 1979-1985, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Membership Lists 1959-1969 (Box 8)
  - Publications from LWV Committees 1969-1982 (Box 8)
  - Voters Service 1964-1979, 12 folders (Box 9)
- Committee Studies
  - Appointments to Commission 1975 (Box 10)
  - Ask the League 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Education 1961-1979 (Box 10)
  - Housing 1965-1975, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - International Relations Foreign Assisstance 1967-1968 (Box 10)
  - International Relations Foreign Policy 1970-1972 (Box 10)
  - International Relations Trade 1967-1973, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - International Relations Trade 1975-1977 (Box 11)
  - Justice 1964-1976 (Box 11)
  - Land Use 1970-1983 (Box 11)
  - Library 1965-1970 (Box 11)
  - Local Government 1967-1977 (Box 11)
  - Local Government Campaign Finance 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Local Government Congress 1971-1973 (Box 11)
  - Recreation 1966-1972 (Box 11)
  - Transportation 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - Urban Crisis 1966-1975 (Box 11)
  - Water Quality 1966-1975 (Box 11)